MUGESH S

XR Generalist

PORTFOLIO

Ambitious XR Designer and Developer with an entrepreneurial drive, bridging imagination and reality since 2019 through challenging problems and hackathons. With over 2 years of experience, I've crafted 50+ AR experiences focused on STEM subjects. Highly motivated to work with early-stage startups and zeroto-one products, I bring a holistic skill set that combines product development, management, and design expertise.

Skills

XR Prototyping

XR development

Spatial Computing

Game/Level Design

Spatial UI/UX

UI/UX Research

Wireframing

Interaction design

Storyboarding

3D Modelling

Animation

Product management

STEM subjects

Tools

Blender, Unity, Bezi, Figma, Adobe Aero, Photoshop, After effects.

Education

B.Tech Information Technology

Anna University, Chennai Sep 2018 - Jun 2022

mugheshambani@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/mugesh



+91 6379964896

Work Experience

XR Designer

MYRACLE.IO, DEC 2021 - Present

- Crafted over 50+ AR experiences for STEM subjects
- Showcased in **Shark Tank India** to over **100 million+** viewers
- Collaborated with biz dev in handling shark tank wave, Optimized in-app purchase pricing and freemium limits with user behaviour analysis
- Mentored over 300+ students on Game design workshops
- Leading concept research, spatial design, prototyping and development of product for over 2+ years

Research & Development Intern

Vaayusastra Aerospace, May 2021 - Oct 2021

• Published a research paper on a telemetry device used by army soldiers at the Siachen Glacier for the Defence Research and Development Organization (DRDO) India.

3D Visualizer - Intern

My Furnish Store, May 2021 - Jul 2021

• Crafting 3D assets for a Augmented Reality based furniture and home decor application

Achievements

Smart India Hackathon 2020 - Winners

Millimetre Wave Based passenger scanner

- Pioneered a novel approach using millimeter waves to penetrate targets and capture reflected waves for high-resolution images.
- Simulated the concept in Blender, leading to win the hackathon

SAP Labs Semicolon Hackathon 2019 - Finalist

Brain Machine Interface for IoT

- · Made a project on controlling machines with brain EEG waves
- EEG waves from the brain are non-invasively measured using a singlechannel wireless sensor and used to perform specific tasks

Augmented Reality Open Program

School of Innovation India from Facebook

Augmented Reality Design and Development Scholarship Program by Facebook, exclusively awarded to 100 students across India.